{
    "id": "6a0d8b25569b44adb4479a341f5e1c7c",
    "title": "Infinitive Or Ing Form",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I dislike people ………………………… me what to do.",
            "description": "Dislike is usually followed by object + ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "telling",
                "to tell",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b10f62e42e9943a0ae81528960dcc005"
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t think that his books deserve …………………………",
            "description": "After deserve the –ing form has a passive meaning. We can also express this idea with a passive infinitive: I don’t think that his books deserve to be read.",
            "answers": [
                "reading",
                "to be read",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "40df3b25d73a4be7aed8b311bb1c02db"
        },
        {
            "question": "Nobody can stop him from ……………………………. what he wants.",
            "description": "The verb stop is followed by object + from + ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "doing",
                "to do",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "846e65fc200b4cf09cd08ca2256e83b0"
        },
        {
            "question": "She prevented me from ……………………….. her room.",
            "description": "The verb prevent is followed by object + from + ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "entering",
                "to enter",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "b611ffdbe0f248169c06954408314548"
        },
        {
            "question": "She didn’t want me ………………………..",
            "description": "The verb want is followed by object + infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "going",
                "to go",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4774cff7d9064546a9ba169f0da539eb"
        },
        {
            "question": "The doctor suggested ………………………….. a long holiday.",
            "description": "The verb suggest cannot be followed by a to-infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "to take",
                "to taking",
                "taking"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "1e5504cd02ad44f2afdcca1ae4f63721"
        },
        {
            "question": "Byron woke up one day ………………………… himself famous.",
            "description": "We often use infinitive clauses to say what somebody found out at the end of a task.",
            "answers": [
                "finding",
                "to find",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9aee92c7e5874f6e875e0b155f37f37b"
        },
        {
            "question": "The plants need …………………………",
            "description": "The ing form has a passive meaning after the verb need. The same idea can be expressed with a passive infinitive: The plants need to be pruned.",
            "answers": [
                "to prune",
                "pruning",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "53a087eaede54322bdfecc1f6d335b7a"
        },
        {
            "question": "She burst out ………………………. when she saw him.",
            "description": "The verb burst out is usually followed by –ing forms.",
            "answers": [
                "to laugh",
                "laughing",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "6fc24d527111423fa1b495a04199ea2e"
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t mind ……………………….. care of young babies.",
            "description": "Mind is usually followed by an –ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "taking",
                "to take",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "79cdf9aa62d44e9b89e7094971c6850e"
        },
        {
            "question": "She is very good ………………………….problems.",
            "description": "Many adjectives are followed by preposition + ing form. Good is one of them.",
            "answers": [
                "to solve",
                "at solving",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4faf8dc0fc234d4f8a18ce93d2495cae"
        },
        {
            "question": "We have a good chance …………………………..",
            "description": "After some nouns we can use either an ing form or an infinitive with little difference of meaning. Chance is one of them. ",
            "answers": [
                "of winning",
                "to win",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "36d9e532cf924c92b81d7026d67cd9be"
        }
    ]
}